AHMED (FARGHALY) ABDALMETAAL

42-830 Stainton Dr , Mississauga, ON, L5C 2Z3 · (647) 972-7631 Sami.farghaly@gmail.com · Portfolio: https://afarghaly.com

A Mineral Resources Engineering graduate with experience in the Finance Industry as a Financial Advisor. Both AWS Solution Architect Associate and AWS Developer Associate Candidate. Web services developer, design, and database analysis. Excellent presentation and communications skills, with eagerness to learn about innovations, new technologies, and leadership skills. Seek and try to inspire innovation and creativity in the workplace, and enjoys problem solving, versatility, quick learner and team player. Dedicated to being a pioneer in cloud computing and cloud services

SKILLS

- Amazon Web Services
- Python
- Front-end web development
- Back-end web development
- NodeJS
- ReactJS

- Problem Solving.
- Communication
- Teamwork
- JSON/ YAML
- JavaScript
- Database Developer (MySQL & NoSQL)
- Data analysis
- MS Excel, MS Word
- MS Access
- Splunk
- Tableau v10
- AngularJS

EXPERIENCE

MAY 2018 - PRESENT

AMAZON WEB SERVICE ARCHITECT/ DEVEOP, SALIENT EDGE – SAN FRANCISCO

Evaluated the company's current cloud infrastructure.

Architected improvement to the current infrastructure to make it fault-tolerant and reliable. Prepared a full Evaluation and recommendation report.

Started provisioning the present recommendation in the proposal submitted

MAR 2018 - PRESENT

DATABASE DEVELOPER, START-UP – MISSISSAUGA, ON

A creation of a database to clone Instagram application. Using one-to-many and many-to-many relationships, tables, and triggers. Data analysis process application through the usage of queries, join tables (inner, left, or right), aggregate functions, and logical operation has been performed on the data to gather information such as identify the most popular photo, identify inactive users, most popular photos, and finding bots.

NOV 2014 - MAR 2015

SNR TECHNICAL ASSISTANT, KUWAIT OIL COMPANY – AL AHMADI, KUWAIT

Designed Relational Database system (RDS) in tight deadline period to digitalize data. Transformed data into reports by creating excel KPI Dashboard and Presented the analytics and results to senior engineers to devise data-driven decisions.

AUG 2016 - MAR 2017

FINANCIAL ADVISOR, EDWARD JONES - MISSISSAUGA, ON

Skills employed: Sales, Communication, leadership, responsibility, problem solving, decisiveness, self-motivation, customer service, and time management

COURSES

- AWS Solution Architect Associate Course Jan 2018 – Mar 2018
- AWS Developer Associate Course April 2018 – April 2018
- The Modern Python 3 Bootcamp June 2018 June 2018
- The Ultimate MySQL Bootcamp Mar 2018 - Mar 2018
- Web Developer Bootcamp Jan 2018 June 2018
- Tableau v10 A-Z June 2018 June 2018
- The Complete Splunk Beginner Course -Mar 2018
 2018

CERTIFICATIONS

- AWS Solution Architect Associate Oct 2018
- AWS SysOps Admin Associate –Nov 2018
- AWS Developer Associate Sep 2018
- CSC,LLQP, & CPH Aug 2018

RELEVANT PROJECTS

MAR 2018 - MAR 2018

CLOUD DEVEOP, https://fekret.cloud

From end to end web application which is considered a playground for the services and applications I develop

EDUCATION

MAY 2014

B.ENG, DALHOUSIE UNIVERSITY – HALIFAX, NS

Major in Mineral Resources and Minor in Mining with 1 year accomplished of Industrial Engineering where I have learned SQL Language

MAY 2016

CONTINOUS STUDIES, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Accomplished passing the CFA (charted financial analyst) level 1 course which prepares the student to pass the exam and also Foundation of Quality and Process Excellence which the first course towards lean six sigma greenbelt